<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Faces &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/faces/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 08:41:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Some Mac With No Cheese</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/20/some-mac-with-no-cheese/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/20/some-mac-with-no-cheese/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2006 08:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Faces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Richards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ringo Starr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rod Stewart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rolling Stones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ron Wood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Nerd is back, the Nerd is back! Sorry about my extended absence but writer&#8217;s block is one hell of a problem! After a little boat trip down in Virginia, I feel refreshed and ready to write about more cool, obscure sounds so let&#8217;s get to it. When I got back from my little boat &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/20/some-mac-with-no-cheese/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Some Mac With No Cheese"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
      The Nerd is back, the Nerd is back! Sorry about my extended absence but writer&#8217;s block is one hell of a problem! After a little boat trip down in Virginia, I feel refreshed and ready to write about more cool, obscure sounds so let&#8217;s get to it.</p>
<p>      When I got back from my little boat ride, I was excited to find in my mailbox a package from the fine folks at Gott Records (look them up at gottrecords.com) featuring a great reissue CD of Faces keyboardist and all around great guy Ian McLagan&#8217;s two solo albums from the late &#8217;70&#8217;s and early &#8217;80&#8217;s.</p>
<p>      Originally a member of the Small Faces when they were a psychedelic rock act fronted by Steve Marriot and turning out masterpieces like Ogden&#8217;s Nut Gone Flake, McLagan remained with the band when they metamorphised (did I just make up a word?) into simply Faces after Marriot quit and Rod Stewart and Ron Wood joined.<br />
      As the band turned their psychedelic leanings into more of a good-time boogie-rock band, McLagan&#8217;s fine organ and piano work came even further into the fore as a perfect complement to Wood&#8217;s slide guitar skronk and bassist Ronnie Lane&#8217;s genius bass playing.        </p>
<p>      All good things must come to an end, though, and when Stewart and Wood each found their side careers going in different directions (Stewart&#8217;s as a solo star and Wood as a member of The Rolling Stones) the Faces broke up, leaving several great albums in their wake, the best of which is undoubtedly A Nod Is As Good As A Wink, though Ohh La La is great as well.</p>
<p>      It didn&#8217;t take McLagan long after the Faces split in 1975 to get his own solo career going. With help from Ron Wood, Keith Richards, Ringo Starr and a host of other British rock vets, the ex-Face recorded the aptly named Troublemaker album in 1977. Though no hit singles were forthcoming, the album should not be penalized for that and is actually one of the best pseudo-pub rock/party rock records ever produced. If only more rockers would drop the airs and just let loose in the studio the world would be a better place. It&#8217;s like no one would start rocking if there was any gin left in the building. Fabulous.</p>
<p>      McLagan followed up Troublemaker with Bump In The Night in 1981. Again, Wood was on board for some hellacious slide guitar playing but this time McLagan ditched some of his guest stars in favor of his touring band. While not as bombastic as his first solo album, Bump In The Night is far more cohesive with more emphasis placed on the songs instead of the atmosphere. Again, no hit singles resulted and McLagan eventually turned his career into that of a well-known and much-respected session player and touring sideman. </p>
<p>      He has played with the best because he is one of the best, leaving a ton of fine recordings both solo and with the Faces incarnations in his wake. Fortunately, the new millenium brought a return to solo recording for McLagan, who has put out the fine album Best Of British on the Gadfly label as well as a few other discs including a new live one available at his website ianmclagan.com</p>
<p>      Sadly, a few weeks ago his wife (the former Kim Moon) passed away in a car wreck. I only have best wishes for him as he and his music have brought a ton of joy into my life, I hope he is able to overcome this adversity and continue to make great music.       </p>
<p>      Please pick up any of McLagan&#8217;s solo work or his work with Small Faces and regular Faces. Even his session work will make you smile. Anyone who wants to take the piss out of rock and rool and just have one hell of a rocking time is sure to love anything he has done.<br />
      Would you like some Mac?</p>
<p>      The Music Nerd knows&#8230;&#8230;&#8230;..</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/20/some-mac-with-no-cheese/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Wood If You Could</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/17/you-wood-if-you-could/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/17/you-wood-if-you-could/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2006 15:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bill Wyman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keith Richards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rod Stewart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rolling Stones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ron Wood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was digging around one of my closets where I keep my Stones and Stones-affiliated CDs yesterday (now there&#8217;s an idea for a blog &#8211; CD/music organization!) and ran across a few Ron Wood solo CDs I hadn&#8217;t played in a while. Being a huge Wood fan (insert appropriate joke here)I figured I would use &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/17/you-wood-if-you-could/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "You Wood If You Could"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was digging around one of my closets where I keep my Stones and Stones-affiliated CDs yesterday (now there&#8217;s an idea for a blog &#8211; CD/music organization!) and ran across a few Ron Wood solo CDs I hadn&#8217;t played in a while. Being a huge Wood fan (insert appropriate joke here)I figured I would use this space to extoll the virtues of the Stones&#8217; longest-running second guitarist (31 years membership!).</p>
<p>When thinking about Ron Wood, one must start at the British beat group Birds, move through The Creation and Jeff Beck Group (where Beck relegated Wood to bass so the mercurial Beck wouldn&#8217;t have to compete axe-wise) and start honing in on one of the best and most-underappreciated boogie bands of all time, The Faces. Wood joined the Faces (originally the Small Faces &#8211; check out Ogden&#8217;s Nut Gone Flake for a pre-Wood psychedelic masterpiece) after forming an alliance with Rod Stewart who was in the Jeff Beck Group with Wood at the time.</p>
<p>Wood and Stewart both joined Faces to shore up the band when guitarist/singer Steve Marriot left to start Humble Pie. Wood then began a long and proud association with the best of sleazy rock and roll that, for all intents and purposes, out-Stoned the Stones.</p>
<p>In the last phase of the Faces&#8217; lifespan, Wood started putting out solo albums, great ones like I&#8217;ve Got My Own Album To Do and Now Look. Both these albums were all-star love-fests that also featured fellow Brit rockers like Stewart, Keith Richards and Mick Jagger among others. Wood was already drifting into the Stones orbit and joined after The Great Guitarist Hunt the Stones had in 1975 during the making of Black and Blue.</p>
<p>Throughout Wood&#8217;s tenure in the Stones he has continued to put out solo albums, the strongest being 19078&#8217;s Gimme Some Neck. The CD is filled with Stones-like raunch and Woody&#8217;s Dylan-like gin-soaked vocals. It is very hard to find but still in print.</p>
<p>Wood fans would also beinterested in tracking down 1982&#8217;s 1234, which is out of print in the US but contains Wood jamming with several members of Devo and a few other obscure bands. Woody has always done it for rock and roll, and not just to get on the radio, and that always speaks volumes to me about a musician&#8217;s motivation and heart.</p>
<p>I could tell you about Wood&#8217;s artwork, which is genius, but that&#8217;s for another blog. Track down some of his solo work and tell me if some of it isn&#8217;t better than most of the schlock the Stones have passed off for music in the past twenty years or so.</p>
<p>Wood you if you could?</p>
<p>The Music Nerd knows&#8230;&#8230;&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/17/you-wood-if-you-could/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
