<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Juviley &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/lost-in-the-grooves-2/artists-exclusive-mp3scds/juviley/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 20:38:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Juviley &#8211; How to Miss The Ground</title>
		<link>/2008/04/14/juviley/</link>
					<comments>/2008/04/14/juviley/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2008 20:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Juviley]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Juviley&#39;s debut CD How to Miss The Ground is a featured Lost in the Grooves release. Click here to sample the music or purchase. Juviley is the project of Israeli musician Or Zubalsky, who toured widely with Israel&#39;s leading indie acts Shy Nobleman, Geva Alon, Daphna &#38; The Cookies. At 21, he began writing his &#8230; <a href="/2008/04/14/juviley/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Juviley &#8211; How to Miss The Ground"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Juviley&#39;s debut CD <em>How to Miss The Ground</em> is a featured Lost in the Grooves release. Click <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results.php?cd=MMG+382&amp;artist=245">here</a> to sample the music or purchase.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/2413324987/" title="Juviley cover by richardschave, on Flickr"><img loading="lazy" src="https://farm4.static.flickr.com/3284/2413324987_59f226edf6_o.jpg" width="200" height="200" alt="Juviley cover" /></a></p>
<p>Juviley is the project of Israeli musician Or Zubalsky, who toured widely with Israel&#39;s leading indie acts Shy Nobleman, Geva Alon, Daphna &amp; The Cookies. At 21, he began writing his own songs, and revealed a tender, delicate sensibility far removed from the stereotypical dumb drummer. Inspired by the chamber pop of Brian Wilson, Nick Drake and Belle and Sebastian, on his debut album <em>How To Miss The Ground</em> Or plays nearly every instrument himself. With its heartbreaking simplicity, bittersweet melodies and thoughtful arrangements it creates a unique, dreamlike atmosphere. Once the record was completed, Or moved to New York City, where he plays regularly, in clubs and on the streets.</p>
<p>The critics love Juviley&#39;s <em>How To Miss The Ground.</em> Palebear muses, &quot;I sort of needed this album to right my sanity&#8230; beautiful, pastoral&#8230; equal parts Kings of Convenience, Mojave 3 and Belle and Sebastian.&quot; And Caroline Leonardo says it&#39;s &quot;an articulate collection of songs sure to warm your soul with pleasant melodies and story-like lyrics&#8230; an acoustic dream with the kind of tunes that&#39;ll lift your spirits during a rainy day&#8230; [it] is one of those rare debuts that carry a lot of clout. This well orchestrated album comes off gentle and well meaning without being pretentious or overbearing in the way that it&#39;s so simple and true. Indie pop has never sounded so good.&quot; </p>
<p>You can also visit with Juviley on <a href="https://www.myspace.com/juviley" target="_blank">MySpace</a>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2008/04/14/juviley/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
