<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Island Records &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/island-records/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 05:06:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Lewis Taylor Re-ducks</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/12/07/lewis-taylor-re-ducks/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/12/07/lewis-taylor-re-ducks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 05:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Al Green]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fleetwood Mac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hacktone Records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Island Records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewis Taylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shout! Factory]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Those of you with only short-term memory faculties working will note my last blog was about a genius psychedelic neo-soul one-man-band type by the name of Lewis Taylor. Well, that blog immediately started some things in motion as far as gathering info on this eccentric artist. Within one day after publishing the blog here I &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/12/07/lewis-taylor-re-ducks/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Lewis Taylor Re-ducks"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>    Those of you with only short-term memory faculties working will note my last blog was about a genius psychedelic neo-soul one-man-band type by the name of Lewis Taylor.</p>
<p>    Well, that blog immediately started some things in motion as far as gathering info on this eccentric artist. Within one day after publishing the blog here I heard from the owners of Hacktone Records concerning what I had written regarding them and their artist.</p>
<p>    First off, it seems the kind but obviously jealous folks at Shout! Factory had lied to me regarding the status of the Hacktone label. It is, in fact, NOT defunct but has simply changed distributors and has chosen not to work with the fine, fibbing folks at Shout! Factory any more.</p>
<p>    Secondly, they report Lewis Taylor has recovered from the nodes on his vocal cords and continues to work on new music for eventual release. While it is too late to promote the US release of the album Stoned (which is four years old anyway), it does mean new material will be released eventually from Taylor.</p>
<p>    The label also informed me that, in the meantime, another Lewis Taylor album will be released in early 2007. Titled The Lost Album, it is about a decade old, and was recorded between Taylor&#8217;s first and second albums on Island but has never been released.</p>
<p>    Seems that Taylor&#8217;s disgust at Island Records for not knowing how to promote him lead Taylor to go into the studio and record an album totally removed from the rich, swirling soul music of his first Island record. Instead of sweet soul, Taylor recorded some bristling rock music modeled more after Fleetwood Mac than Al Green. After laying the tracks down and working all of the anger out of his system, Taylor decided to shelve the tracks and instead went back to preparing for another Island album full of his trademark psychedelic soul music.</p>
<p>    Now that he is long removed from his Island experience, Taylor has been slowly releasing these tracks. First as a freebie passed out at his gigs and then for sale strictly at his website. Now, the fellas at Hacktone are releasing the record to the world. Again, it seems to be a one-man-band affair and promises a new look at a Taylor so few have heard regardless.</p>
<p>    Though newer music would be better than another old album, I am happy to be getting anything at all from this reclusive artist. Hacktone reports that Lewis just hates to tour so whatever albums we get are all we are going to get from Taylor so if we want to experience his genius, we have to take what he and his label give us.</p>
<p>    So I will. And I will be happy about it.</p>
<p>    Getting to hear the genius will be enough.</p>
<p>    When the album comes out, expect a review here. Please pick it up regardless, as it will no doubt blow your mind like Stoned did  to me.</p>
<p>    The Music Nerd knows&#8230;&#8230;&#8230;.. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/12/07/lewis-taylor-re-ducks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
