<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>george martin &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/george-martin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 15:38:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Be My Mighty Baby</title>
		<link>/2007/05/04/be-my-mighty-baby/</link>
					<comments>/2007/05/04/be-my-mighty-baby/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 15:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[george martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mighty Baby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pink floyd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Rex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Beatles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Kinks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yes, me again! Back so soon with real groovy tunes so grabs ya a spoon and start digging in! Fans of &#8217;60&#8217;s British garage pop and R&#038;B have no doubt heard of the great band The Action (and if you haven&#8217;t, check them out now!!!) so those fans will no doubt be thrilled when they &#8230; <a href="/2007/05/04/be-my-mighty-baby/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Be My Mighty Baby"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>  Yes, me again! Back so soon with real groovy tunes so grabs ya a spoon and start digging in! </p>
<p>  Fans of &#8217;60&#8217;s British garage pop and R&#038;B have no doubt heard of the great band The Action (and if you haven&#8217;t, check them out now!!!) so those fans will no doubt be thrilled when they find out The Action morphed and became a totally different band at one point.</p>
<p>  Below is a review of Sunbeam&#8217;s recent reissue of one of the best of The Action&#8217;s post-Action albums.</p>
<p>Mighty Baby &#8211; A Jug Of Love<br />
Sunbeam Records</p>
<p>  Thanks to the great, great Sunbeam label we can again enjoy the thrilling psychedelic sounds of one of the most overlooked psychedelic bands ever to arise out of England. I, for one, have been waiting for this album to be reissued for a mighty (baby) long time! This reissue of this underrated band&#8217;s second album from 1972 is like manna from the heavens for those searching for long-lost psyche.</p>
<p>  For those looking for a little more backstory, Mighty Baby rose from the ashes of another great overlooked British band, The Action. For a while The Action had been tagged as the band most ready to take over from The Beatles, and unlikely as it seems today, if you listen to The Action&#8217;s early recordings you will wonder why they didn&#8217;t do just that.</p>
<p>  No less than Fab Four producer George Martin thought so as well, as he signed them to their recording contract. Come to think of it, he signed wimp-rock band America too so maybe ol&#8217; Georgy&#8217;s taste is suspect. But that&#8217;s another story. To Martin&#8217;s credit, The Action really did kick some major ass. Mixing equal parts of the Beatles&#8217; (and the other Merseybeat bands) melodic savvy with the pure rock power of the Who and Kinks, The Action were a powerhouse band that nonetheless didn&#8217;t quite get the breaks necessary to really hit it big.</p>
<p>  After a couple of personnel, managerial, label, and even name changes, the remnants of The Action signed with the same management team as Pink Floyd and T-Rex and started experimenting in the studio. Unlike most hard R&#038;B bands who attempted to keep up with the times by embracing the mind-bending sounds of psychedelic rock, the sound seemed natural and not forced and the current line-up seemed adept at playing the new, groundbreaking sub-genre of rock music. </p>
<p>  Christened Mighty Baby by the band&#8217;s new label in an attempt at a new start, the former Action came up with one of the stronger psychedelic albums of the period, an album that stands up with the Beatles&#8217; Sgt. Pepper and the Pretty Things&#8217; S.F. Sorrow as psychedelic rock blueprints. </p>
<p>  Sadly, it went mostly unheard. </p>
<p>  Dropped from their label, the band managed to hook up with Blue Horizon Records for this reissue, their second and final album. Though as good as their first record, at the time it still unfortunately succumbed to the same fate: little airplay and hardly any sales. The times had changed and most succesful bands were either playing soft rock like Crosby, Stills and Nash or a simpler form of boogie/blues-based hard rock like Led Zeppelin which would later sadly evolve into the ear-wrecking sounds of heavy metal. For a band more interested in melody, extended fluid guitar lines and thriling vocal harmonies, the time had definitely passed. But that doesn&#8217;t mean this album isn&#8217;t bliss personified. </p>
<p>  A psychedelic fan&#8217;s dream with exquisite melodic playing and guitar work to make your heart soar to the heavens, this album makes me wish we could return to the &#8217;60&#8217;s for just a little while. Energetic with none of the excessive noodling marring most psyche albums, it&#8217;s a perfect meld of garage and psyche that will stay on your turntable for weeks.</p>
<p>  Fans of psyche will wet their pants over this one. Pick it up, turn on and tune out, babies. Get some of whatever stuff you smoke when your parents aren&#8217;t around and start a-hootin&#8217; because this shit is THE shit. One of the most excellent psyche albums around from one of the most underrated bands ever. Get you some Action and some Mighty Baby as soon as you can. You will not be sorry, and I will guarantee it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/05/04/be-my-mighty-baby/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>David and Jonathan &#8211; &#8220;David and Jonathan&#8221; CD (RPM)</title>
		<link>/2006/09/08/david-and-jonathan-david-and-jonathan-cd-rpm/</link>
					<comments>/2006/09/08/david-and-jonathan-david-and-jonathan-cd-rpm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2006 18:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[beatles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[george martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper/ LITG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roger cook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roger greenaway]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The early success of the Beatles spawned a slew of nice boy popsters on the foggy side of the pond, and &#8220;David and Jonathan&#8221; (actually Rogers Cook and Greenaway, writing their own songs but performing pseudonymously from 1965-68) were so especially nice that George Martin himself produced their sides and let them have a crack &#8230; <a href="/2006/09/08/david-and-jonathan-david-and-jonathan-cd-rpm/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "David and Jonathan &#8211; &#8220;David and Jonathan&#8221; CD (RPM)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000EWBNEG/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook"><img src="https://images.amazon.com/images/P/B000EWBNEG.01.MZZZZZZZ.jpg" alt="Medium Image" /></a></p>
<form action="https://buybox.amazon.com/o/dt/assoc/handle-buy-box=asin" method="post"><input type="hidden" name="asin.B000EWBNEG" value="1" /><input type="hidden" name="tag-value" value="bubblegumbook" /><input type="hidden" name="tag_value" value="bubblegumbook" /><input type="image" name="submit.add-to-cart" value="Buy from Amazon.com" src="https://rcm-images.amazon.com/images/G/01/associates/add-to-cart.gif" alt="Buy from Amazon.com" border="0" /></form>
<p>The early success of the Beatles spawned a slew of nice boy popsters on the foggy side of the pond, and &#8220;David and Jonathan&#8221; (actually Rogers Cook and Greenaway, writing their own songs but performing pseudonymously from 1965-68) were so especially nice that George Martin himself produced their sides and let them have a crack at &#8220;Michelle,&#8221; a top 20 hit in the US. In time, the duo would reclaim their names and become important producer-songwriters (&#8220;You&#8217;ve Got Your Troubles,&#8221; &#8220;I&#8217;d Like To Teach The World To Sing&#8221;), but first they dropped themselves into the gumball machine, with this turn offering idealistic folkster crooning over harpsichord (&#8220;Lovers of the World Unite&#8221;), the next nonsense big band bubblepop silliness (&#8220;Gilly Gilly Ossenfeffer Katzennellenbogen By The Sea&#8221;), and then anxious Beatle-penned melodrama (&#8220;She&#8217;s Leaving Home&#8221;). Dig lush production, Chad, Jeremy, Peter, Gordon and the Freddie? Then this, luv, is for you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/09/08/david-and-jonathan-david-and-jonathan-cd-rpm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
