<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Paul Nelson &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/paul-nelson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 07:07:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Blue Ash</title>
		<link>/2006/07/02/blue-ash/</link>
					<comments>/2006/07/02/blue-ash/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Frankiefane]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 07:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bill Bartolin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Ash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Evans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frank Secich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Kendzor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Nelson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rozniata]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Ash is glad and honored to be part of the &#34;Lost In The Grooves&#34; family. This is a brief history of&#160;the band. Blue Ash was formed in 1969 by Frank Secich (bass guitar), Jim Kendzor (vocals), Bill &#34;Goog&#34; Yendrek (lead guitar) and David Evans (drums). The band debuted at a psychedelic club called &#34;The &#8230; <a href="/2006/07/02/blue-ash/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Blue Ash"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blue Ash is glad and honored to be part of the &quot;Lost In The Grooves&quot; family. This is a brief history of&nbsp;the band. Blue Ash was formed in 1969 by Frank Secich (bass guitar), Jim Kendzor (vocals), Bill &quot;Goog&quot; Yendrek (lead guitar) and David Evans (drums). The band debuted at a psychedelic club called &quot;The Freak Out&quot; in Youngstown, Ohio on October 3, 1969. Determined to go against the then omnipresent long-guitar-solo-jam bands, Blue Ash would forge a style in the manner of their own teen-aged years heroes: Beatles, Who, Kinks, Byrds, Beau Brummels, Hollies, Rolling Stones, Yardbirds, and many others mixed in from the mid-60&#8217;s. Coupled with a wild stage-show and the management of Geoffrey Jones, Blue Ash soon became very popular on the teen-dance and club circuit of PA, NY, Ohio and W.VA. In October of 1970, guitarist Bill Yendrek was replaced by Bill Bartolin. For the next few years Blue Ash played a hectic 200-250 dates a year throughout the region. During that time the songwriting team of Secich-Bartolin were stockpiling an enormous amount of original material.&nbsp;In 1972, they were signed to a recording contract with Mercury Records by the late , great (legendary A&amp;R man/ rock writer)&nbsp;Paul Nelson. Paul also signed&nbsp;&quot; The New York Dolls&quot;&nbsp;around the same time.&nbsp;Their debut lp &quot;No More, No Less&quot; (1973) received rhapsodic reviews in the rock press. Blue Ash along with Big Star and Raspberries became critical darlings of a new sound later to be called &quot;power pop&quot;. With not enough sales or FM airplay came the death knell to the first wave of 70&#8217;s power pop bands. Blue Ash continued on and in 1977 released a 2nd lp on Playboy Records. In 1979 the band broke up. In the ensuing years Blue Ash developed a world-wide cult following with many groups recording their songs: Records, Finkers, Michael Monroe to name a few. Over the years there was rumoured to be tons of unreleased Blue Ash material. In 2004, Not Lame Records released a 2CD set of it with 44 songs called &quot;Around Again&quot;. Blue Ash is now reformed (but not too reformed) and play out occasionally. The band consists of all 4 original members plus 2nd drummer Jeff Rozniata, Bob Darke (bass) and Brian Wingrove (piano, vocals). For more about Blue Ash go to: <a href="https://www.blueashmusic.com/">www.BlueAshMusic.com</a> &nbsp;and&#8230;. <a href="https://launch.groups.yahoo.com/group/BlueAsh/">https://launch.groups.yahoo.com/group/BlueAsh/</a> </p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <a href="https://blueashmusic.com/
<a href="https://photobucket.com/" target="_blank"><img src="https://i145.photobucket.com/albums/r233/Frankiefane/8a80.jpg" border="0" alt="Photo Sharing and Video Hosting at Photobucket"></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/07/02/blue-ash/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
