<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>prank calls &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/prank-calls/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 08:52:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>The Communists Are Coming To Kill Us/Prank Calls</title>
		<link>/2006/03/08/john-trubee/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/08/john-trubee/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 08:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artists (exclusive MP3s/CDs)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chas glynn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank zappa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free jazz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Trubee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john trubee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matt groening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prank calls]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John Trubee&#8217;s The Communists Are Coming to Kill Us! is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive, available now from Maryatt Music Group. Click to sample John&#8217;s singles collection or purchase. John Trubee&#8217;s legendary Prank Call CDs, available as MP3 samples, downloads or full CDs: Greatest Prank Phone Calls Of All Time Vol. 1 Greatest Prank &#8230; <a href="/2006/03/08/john-trubee/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Communists Are Coming To Kill Us/Prank Calls"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>John Trubee&#8217;s <em>The Communists Are Coming to Kill Us!</em> is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive, available <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/store/cd_info.php?id=MMG+303" target="_blank">now</a> from Maryatt Music Group. <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+213&#038;artist=167" target="_blank">Click</a> to sample John&#8217;s singles collection or purchase.</p>
<p>John Trubee&#8217;s legendary Prank Call CDs, available as MP3 samples, downloads or full CDs:</p>
<p><strong>Greatest Prank Phone Calls Of All Time <a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+264&#038;artist=167">Vol. 1</a></strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+264&#038;artist=167"> </a><br /> <strong>Greatest Prank Phone Calls Of All Time <a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+265&#038;artist=197">Vol. 2</a><br /> </strong><strong>Greatest Prank Phone Calls Of All Time <a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+266&#038;artist=196">Vol. 3</a></strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+266&#038;artist=196"> </a><br /> <strong>Greatest Prank Phone Calls Of All Time <a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+267&#038;artist=167">Vol. 4</a></strong><a target="_blank" href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+267&#038;artist=167"> </a> </p>
<p>Review:<br /> John Trubee and the Ugly Janitors of America <em>The Communists Are Coming to Kill Us!</em>  (Enigma, 1984)  </p>
<p>Mr. Trubee is best known as the man behind &ldquo;Blind Man&rsquo;s Penis,&rdquo; a demented poem with lines like &ldquo;Warts love my nipples because they are pink/Vomit on me baby, yeah, yeah&rdquo; that was sent to a song-poem mill and turned into a deadpan country song which subsequently became an underground novelty hit. Lesser known, but far stranger, is his follow-up album. Trubee got the ball rolling by sending a fake suicide note to several associates, including L.A. Reader rock critic Matt Groening and Enigma&rsquo;s Bill Hein, who agreed to meet with Trubee and negotiate a record deal. In Trubee&rsquo;s words: &ldquo;It was no negotiation. I wanted to do the record badly&#8211;that was obvious. It was similar to a horny teenage boy negotiating with a supermodel to lose his virginity. There is no deal&#8211;he just gets with her fast before she changes her mind. I told Bill I&#8217;d do it for no money. He set up mastering time at Capitol and I walked in &hellip; with a brown paper bag full of reel tapes and cassettes of teenage poetry rants, prank phone calls, aborted horn chart recordings from music school, and other weirdness. I had the flu and I sat with Eddie Shierer for six hours editing all this madness into an album.&rdquo; What resulted was an extremely unique and, well, odd record. I came across it in a used bin shortly after it came out. It was both annoying as hell and insanely captivating, a collage of atonal avant-jazz, primitive electronic compositions, and spoken rants against stuck-up college girls and the suave men who slept with them, plus those juvenile prank calls, a revelation long before the genre became a pop cultural phenomena. If the record that was attached to the Voyager space probe had contained the sounds of all the alienated, pissed-off, shat-on people on earth, it would sound something like this. (Chas Glynn, from the book <em>Lost in the Grooves</em>) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/08/john-trubee/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
