<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Queen &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/queen/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 16:11:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Time For Some Elf Examination</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/04/time-for-some-elf-examination/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/04/time-for-some-elf-examination/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2006 16:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[beatles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Elf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Sabbath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Queen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is this casual friend of mine who has realised over the past year or so that I am intensely into music and that I am a certifiable Music Nerd. Though he is a fan of metal and knows that I am not so into that subgenre of Rock and Roll, he asked me if &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/04/time-for-some-elf-examination/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Time For Some Elf Examination"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>    <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000003ORJ/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook"><img src="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/B000003ORJ.01.TZZZZZZZ.jpg" alt="Small Image" /></a></p>
<form action="http://buybox.amazon.com/o/dt/assoc/handle-buy-box=asin" method="post"><input type="hidden" name="asin.B000003ORJ" value="1" /><input type="hidden" name="tag-value" value="bubblegumbook" /><input type="hidden" name="tag_value" value="bubblegumbook" /><input type="image" name="submit.add-to-cart" value="Buy from Amazon.com" src="http://rcm-images.amazon.com/images/G/01/associates/add-to-cart.gif" alt="Buy from Amazon.com" border="0" /></form>
<p>    There is this casual friend of mine who has realised over the past year or so that I am intensely into music and that I am a certifiable Music Nerd. Though he is a fan of metal and knows that I am not so into that subgenre of Rock and Roll, he asked me if I had any curios in my CD collection that he might like.</p>
<p>    Knowing he likes other music besides metal (though metal is the main type of music he listens to) I went to my CD vault in hopes I might find a title which would stick out to me as something he would enjoy listening to.</p>
<p>    Fortunately, I had to go no further than the &#8216;B&#8217; section to find something suitable for him.</p>
<p>    He had mentioned in the past he had enjoyed listening to the Beatles, and was a fan of their stuff. So, when I saw a CD by a band that I can only describe as the Evil Beatles, I knew it would be something he would like.</p>
<p>    The band&#8217;s actual moniker is Big Elf and they ROCK!</p>
<p>    Sounding like a cross between The Beatles, Queen and Black Sabbath, they are the only metal band I have found that I like. Over the course of their handful of albums and EPs I have come to respect a band like this who is able to channel their influences into a very unique sound. I mean, this band makes a noise unlike any metal band I&#8217;ve heard but is so tuneful and melodic, with songs so well constructed, I believe this band could unite everyone who likes rock and roll and conquer the world.</p>
<p>    Maybe I am overdoing it but this is the reaction I got when listening to their better-than-great album Money Machine four years ago. Since then I have become a collector of their stuff which is very hard to find. If you want to check out their stuff (even Allmusic had very little to say about them) then go to their website and have a listen. The address is www.bigelf.com and I hope you give them a try. </p>
<p>    My friend, the guy who likes the kind of metal where the vocals sound like grunts and growls, just loves the band now and is attempting to search out their other CDs as we speak. Gratification and validation for me and a great new band to check out for him. </p>
<p>    Ain&#8217;t life grand?</p>
<p>    Have you reconciled with your inner elf?</p>
<p>    The Music Nerd knows&#8230;&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/08/04/time-for-some-elf-examination/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
