<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Robert Johnson &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/robert-johnson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 18:33:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Francois Rabbath</title>
		<link>/2006/08/23/francois-rabbath/</link>
					<comments>/2006/08/23/francois-rabbath/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paul aarstad]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 18:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blue Cheer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Bowie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Aarstad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the who]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyrannosaurus Rex]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My early forays in record collecting were strictly economically determined. With little pocket money, I sought my treasures in out-of-the-way places and bought them cheap. Happily, this led to some life-enhancing discoveries: The Who Sing My Generation and Sell Out, right there at the corner drugstore. The Man Who Sold the World, a remaindered Mercury &#8230; <a href="/2006/08/23/francois-rabbath/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Francois Rabbath"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My early forays in record collecting were strictly economically determined. With little pocket money, I sought my treasures in out-of-the-way places and bought them cheap. Happily, this led to some life-enhancing discoveries: <em>The Who Sing My Generation</em> and <em>Sell Out</em>, right there at the corner drugstore. <em>The Man Who Sold the World</em>, a remaindered Mercury copy alongside full-price RCA reissues at the local head shop.<em> A Beard of Stars</em>, complete with &ldquo;Ride a White Swan&rdquo; 7&rdquo;, from an overstock sale at the college bookstore, and a promo copy of <em>Marquee Moon</em> among the rejects outside the college radio station. With the possible exception of the Tyrannosaurus Rex, all were under a dollar; the Television album, otherwise impossible to find where I lived, was free&mdash;and, as the ad says, &ldquo;priceless.&rdquo; </p>
<p>But even closer than these to the core of my musical being is a flukier, more improbable find. One day my mother brought <em>Bass Ball</em> by Fran&ccedil;ois Rabbath home from Woolworth&rsquo;s for my brother, who played string bass. Information about the record stopped with Dom Cerruli&rsquo;s provocative liner notes, which place Rabbath among a <em>nouvelle vague</em> of French jazz. Rabbath and his drummer, Armand Molinetti, serve up twelve elegantly arranged, sonically adventurous tracks. Some are live; others feature bass overdubs&mdash;up to three, but generally no more than one. Maybe it&rsquo;s that <em>Bass Ball</em> is on Philips, but to me it&rsquo;s oddly reminiscent of <em>Vincebus Eruptum</em>. Rabbath is far subtler than Blue Cheer, true, but his multi-tracked basses are sludgily akin to Leigh Stephens&rsquo; guitars. In Rabbath&rsquo;s hands the bass is a protean creature of moods: a gentle flamenco guitar on &ldquo;Ode d&rsquo;Espagne,&rdquo; a cell of screaming lunatics on &ldquo;Basses en Fugue.&rdquo; Heavy metal starts here. </p>
<p>Needless to say, we wore <em>Bass Ball</em> out. Themes from the record soundtracked my dreams. My brother learned to approximate the songs on string bass; he was particularly effective peeling off keening arco harmonics and coughing up abrasive gutturals on &ldquo;Walpurgis.&rdquo; Eventually picking up bass guitar, he evoked Rabbath immediately, effortlessly, unconsciously. </p>
<p>When Spalax&rsquo;s 2003 <em>New Sound of Jazz</em> turned up among Forced Exposure&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.forcedexposure.com/artists/rabbath.francois.html" target="_self">current releases</a>, it was like running into an old friend. The disk compiles stereo versions of Rabbath&rsquo;s 1964 debut and its follow up. (The CD lacks the impact of my mono vinyl, so crank it!) The songs from <em>Bass Ball</em> anticipate absolutely everything: Cale&rsquo;s viola (&ldquo;Prelude a l&rsquo;Archet&rdquo;), the Yardbirds&rsquo; stop-time concussion volleys (&ldquo;Hesitations&rdquo;), Hendrix&rsquo;s technical feats of strength (&ldquo;Impalas&rdquo;), John Theodore and Neil Hagerty&rsquo;s workouts in The Royal Trux (&ldquo;Western a la Breugel&rdquo;). It&rsquo;s still unclear where <em>Bass Ball</em> belongs in the jazz canon. It&rsquo;s new, all right, but it&rsquo;s not free. The word &ldquo;skronk,&rdquo; however, aptly describes its more extreme tonalities. I&rsquo;m happy to report that the tracks from Rabbath&rsquo;s second album don&rsquo;t disappoint. Cut from the same cloth as <em>Bass Ball</em> (though lighter on electronic enhancement), the seven titles are longer and, consequently, even further out.  </p>
<p>Given its rainbow-tinted, strobe-lit cover and gag-inducing title, I was never entirely satisfied that <em>Bass Ball</em> wasn&rsquo;t cornball stuff. It&rsquo;s good to hear that Rabbath is a respected, if obscure presence in French jazz history. Of course he used drugs, as the supremely eerie &ldquo;Bitume&rdquo; always suggested. Spalax&rsquo;s somewhat amateurish packaging does include pictures of the man himself. Not quite the mad hipster of my imagination but no square either: A balding, monkish guy closing his eyes and setting his bow for the heart of the sun.</p>
<p>  For my money, <em>New Sound of Jazz</em> is our era&rsquo;s <em>King of the Delta Blues Singers</em>. (Re)introducing a troubled young virtuoso whose shadow falls quietly across the music of the last forty years, illuminating his story while leaving intact just enough mystery, this reissue is like a portal to a world of howling ghosts. I don&rsquo;t even care if it popularizes a treasured childhood secret. I doubt Rabbath&rsquo;s will ever become a household name. But in a time when a young person can pick up <em>Funhouse</em>, <em>Marquee Moon</em>, and <em>White Light/White Heat</em> from a single aisle at Circuit City, it&rsquo;s nice to know there are still further frontiers&mdash;new sounds in jazz, if you will. Buy this disk and be haunted. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/08/23/francois-rabbath/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
