<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Rounder &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/rounder/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 16:08:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>NRBQ PDQ</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/19/nrbq-pdq/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/19/nrbq-pdq/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 16:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bar bands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NRBQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rounder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terry Adams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Not too much time to write today, unfortunately, so I will probably revisit the topic of NRBQ sometime in the near future. In fact, how about Monday? Right now, I just wanted to hip you to the band if you hadn&#8217;t heard of them. Begun in 1967 and continuing to this day, the band originally &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/19/nrbq-pdq/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "NRBQ PDQ"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not too much time to write today, unfortunately, so I will probably revisit the topic of NRBQ sometime in the near future. In fact, how about Monday? Right now, I just wanted to hip you to the band if you hadn&#8217;t heard of them.</p>
<p>Begun in 1967 and continuing to this day, the band originally known as the New Rythym and Blues Quartet keeps on rocking, putting out great albums on small labels that redefine the term bar-band rock and roll.</p>
<p>For the unitiated, the band has made its&#8217; name being the most versatile musical unit ever created. Through the years the band has backed everyone from Carl Perkins to Skeeter Davis to wrestling legend Lou Albano (that&#8217;s right), Chuck Berry, Johnnie Johnson and just about everyone in between.</p>
<p>Rock legends such as Keith Richards, Paul McCartney and countless others constantly sing their praises and most record some of their songs as well. Blessed with three great song-writers, the band is never short of clever pop songs as well as obtuse, &#8220;out&#8221; songs most of the band&#8217;s fans come to adore more than the sing-along rockers.</p>
<p>The band has put out a ton of records on a ton of labels, most of which are still in print, believe it or not. That alone speaks volumes for the love people have for this semi-underground band.</p>
<p>Your homework for the weekend: go to your local CD hut and find an NRBQ CD or record. It will be well worth your money and will prime you for my next blog, which will be a more detailed discussion of the band and it&#8217;s best recordings.</p>
<p>The Music Nerd knows&#8230;&#8230;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/05/19/nrbq-pdq/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
