<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>jonathan donaldson &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/jonathan-donaldson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 08:47:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Fugu</title>
		<link>/2006/03/08/fugu/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/08/fugu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 08:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Artists (exclusive MP3s/CDs)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cello]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fugu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fugu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harmony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jonathan donaldson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mehdi zannad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orchestral pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postmodern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rococo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fugu&#8217;s debut Fugu EP is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive. Click to sample the music or purchase. Fugu Fugu EP (Semantic, 1996) Fugu is Mehdi Zannad, a classically trained French pianist who discovered he could only compose three-minute songs. Don&#8217;t be fooled by the indie world that tries to &#8220;Hello Kitty-ize&#8221; him. However pretentious &#8230; <a href="/2006/03/08/fugu/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Fugu"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fugu&#8217;s debut <em>Fugu EP</em> is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive. <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+41&#038;artist=62" target="_blank">Click</a> to sample the music or purchase.  </p>
<p>Fugu <em>Fugu EP</em> (Semantic, 1996)  </p>
<p>Fugu is Mehdi Zannad, a classically trained French pianist who discovered he could only compose three-minute songs. Don&rsquo;t be fooled by the indie world that tries to &ldquo;Hello Kitty-ize&rdquo; him. However pretentious Zannad&rsquo;s titles, his music could be taken seriously by the sternest scholars. This self-released EP, which predates debut full-length Fugu 1 by four years, is as despicably rare as it is charming. I was able to obtain a copy directly from Zannad after a Boston performance. His jaw-dropping postmodern Beach Boys deconstructions (complete with four-part harmonies) combined with skillful power pop spelunking led me to confront his timid frame after the set and proclaim, &ldquo;you are my new favorite band!&rdquo; More consistent and battier than Fugu 1, the EP is one of the least boring and most rococo recordings you are ever likely to hear. &ldquo;F29&rdquo; is a trip into a cavern of multi-colored rock candy stalagmites triggered by swift piano arpeggios, skronky Vox organ hits, sweeping cello melodramas and Zannad&rsquo;s own incoherent trilling. Complete with sighing violins, &ldquo;F4&rdquo; evokes a mythological place where the Beatles are composed of two French Paul McCartneys, the Velvet Underground&rsquo;s Sterling Morrison plays his ultra simplistic &ldquo;non-rock&rdquo; leads, and Ringo pats on the muted snare, like on Abbey Road&rsquo;s &ldquo;Something.&rdquo; On &ldquo;Untitled&rdquo; and &ldquo;Interlude,&rdquo; a cacophony of voices and bubbling machines intermingle with gurgling horns and myriad symphonic cutting-room floor clippings before returning to Earth. &ldquo;F26&rdquo; pits the thrush of strummed guitars, frowning horns and cotton candy organ against Zannad&rsquo;s voice on the odd-canticle chorus. While it&rsquo;s possible to be swept up in the obvious magical mystery of his production, or the fractured-ness of his arranging sensibility, there is always at the core an essential song, a framework to shake you of your every sun-baked boredom with pop music. Orgiastic, steeped in utter coherence. (Jonathan Donaldson, from the book <em>Lost in the Grooves</em>) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/08/fugu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
