<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Arthur Alexander &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/arthur-alexander/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 06:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Be Thankful For What You Are Tiven</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/07/11/be-thankful-for-what-you-are-tiven/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/07/11/be-thankful-for-what-you-are-tiven/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 06:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arthur Alexander]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curtis mayfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Covay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jon Tiven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sally Tiven]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hope you all had a Happy Fourth of July! I sure did, and the resulting recovery from said celebrations have made me once again kinda slow on the draw here in blog-land and I am once again begging you to bear with me as I catch up. After a few blogs about the genius of &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/07/11/be-thankful-for-what-you-are-tiven/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Be Thankful For What You Are Tiven"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
     Hope you all had a Happy Fourth of July! I sure did, and the resulting recovery from said celebrations have made me once again kinda slow on the draw here in blog-land and I am once again begging you to bear with me as I catch up.</p>
<p>     After a few blogs about the genius of soul that is Don Covay, I promised I would hip you to a series of tribute CDs to soul heroes which came out in the early-to-mid-&#8217;90&#8217;s on the Razor and Tie label and Shanachie Records.</p>
<p>     The tributes, one each for Curtis Mayfield, Don Covay and Arthur Alexander, were spearheaded by a rocker with Memphis ties, Jon Tiven. For those who are unfamiliar with the name, Tiven has bumped around the music scene since the late &#8217;60&#8217;s but started gaining fame in the mid-&#8217;70&#8217;s as part of the Big Star axis. Although never in that groundbreaking pop band, Tiven played in other bands with various permutations of the members and also counted among his bandmates and collaborators unsung Memphis pop geniuses (and who I will devote future blogs to) Van Duren and Tommy Hoehn.</p>
<p>     Knocking sround Memphis and later New York City, Tiven slowly gained notice as an excellent producer and songwriter, as well as artist in his own right. Many bands and artists have covered Tiven and his bass-playing wife Sally&#8217;s songs over the years and current albums by Ellis Hooks, Shemekia Copeland and Frank Black bear evidence of his song-writing ability and producing skills.  </p>
<p>     Back in the early &#8217;90&#8217;s, Tiven started releasing these great tribute CDs featuring a coterie of great performers like Covay, Ron Wood, members of rock band Living Colour, Dave Edmunds, Nick Lowe, Iggy Pop and on and on. Though they are hard to find today, I suggest searching them out if you can. The performances are all top notch and many feature Tiven and his band playing back-up.</p>
<p>     I am set to interview Tiven soon and I will flesh out the story behind these tributes in a few weeks but I hope you endeavor to search them out and listen to them. They are possibly the best tribute CDs ever in a world that has way too many of them. The artists taking part are showcased well and the artists being honored couldn&#8217;t possibly have their songs lavished with more respect.</p>
<p>     Also keep your eyes peeled for any CD with Tiven&#8217;s name in the credits. He is a throwback to the days when people cared about music and everything he produces has an authentic feel to it. Whenever I stumble across his name on a CD, I pick it up because I know I am going to like it. He has a great ear for new artists, is a great songwriter and has a cool little recording career going himself. An album on Rounder from the late &#8217;90&#8217;s is especially good. Search that out as well.  </p>
<p>     The Music Nerd knows&#8230;..</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/07/11/be-thankful-for-what-you-are-tiven/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
