<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dr. dog easybeat &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/dr-dog-easybeat/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2006 02:14:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Review:  Dr. Dog &#8211; Easybeat</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/11/10/review-dr-dog-easybeat/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/11/10/review-dr-dog-easybeat/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lane Steinberg]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2006 02:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chateauneuf du Pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. dog easybeat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dr. Dog &#8211; Easy Street (National Parking) I love to check out bands on Myspace. That&#8217;s how I find music these days. It&#8217;s a perfectly egalitarian system. You get a few pictures &#038; four songs, whether you&#8217;re Sting or The Hangnails. During one of my semi-inebriated late-night trowels I stumbled onto Dr. Dog. What I &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/11/10/review-dr-dog-easybeat/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Review:  Dr. Dog &#8211; Easybeat"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Dog &#8211; Easy Street (National Parking)</p>
<p>I love to check out bands on Myspace. That&#8217;s how I find music these days. It&#8217;s a perfectly egalitarian system. You get a few pictures &#038; four songs, whether you&#8217;re Sting or The Hangnails. During one of my semi-inebriated late-night trowels I stumbled onto Dr. Dog. What I heard really intrigued me, so I bought their cd, Easybeat. While waiting for it to arrive I read some reviews that mentioned their overt Beatle-ness. A few really slagged them for it, like saying, &#8216;We&#8217;re so over this, dude&#8217;. Well it arrived today and I&#8217;m on listen number six. I suppose it can be called Beatle-esque in that it has harmony, melody, &#038; unexpected juxtapositions of musical elements (i.e. string quartets giving way to garage-band breaks, sing-alongs that pop out of nowhere, feedback over augmented chords). There is nothing here that is ripped from the fabs, save for one tossed-off Obladi-ish bass line on the opening number. Mostly what is Beatle-esque is an obvious striving to make something that&#8217;s going to stick around. Not to say it&#8217;s pretentious or precious in any way, it&#8217;s just that it&#8217;s obvious these guys are shooting for something. There is intent here that goes beyond writing a good or even catchy song. And like the Beatles, it walks the line between melancholia and jubilation, often in the same song. Mostly, it sounds like a band in a room dicking around and having a lot of fun. Sonically, It has the weird lo-fi weirdness of the Basement Tapes. No high end at all, which is kinda neat. Gives the ears an unexpected rest. It was recorded on a 1/4&#8243; 8-track, probably the same Fostex I have in my closet. It&#8217;s a magical little machine that may have contributed to the discs hazy mood. There are correlations between Easybeat &#038; the two Simon Dawes EP&#8217;s, which have a similar fly-by-the-seat sound of the Kinks recording in a tool shed. Like the Dawes records, vocals distort, people go off microphone, and ragged harmonies are left in with the spot-on ones. Such a simple act, and one that could be interpreted as a careless one, but the bravery of leaving the grit in results in a sound that&#8217;s soothingly human, a sound you can snuggle up to. Couple that with the great songs these guys write, and you got something that&#8217;s essential. I hope no one gives them a budget for the next record, either.</p>
<p>www.myspace.com/drdog </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/11/10/review-dr-dog-easybeat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
