<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>dream warriors &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/dream-warriors/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 06:57:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>&#8220;recalls Creem Magazine at its most prickly&#8221; (Eye Weekly)</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/recalls-creem-magazine-at-its-most-prickly-eye-weekly/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/recalls-creem-magazine-at-its-most-prickly-eye-weekly/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 06:57:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Reviews (cont.)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream warriors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye weekly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kylie minogue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rick moody]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stooges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the tubes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#34;To point out that the staff at your local indie record store are about as tightly wound and implacable as the Taliban has already become a clich&#233;. In contrast to that stalwart stance, Scram Magazine has become known for a distinct lack of smugness while digging through the dollar bins of history. Most pop-storians are &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/recalls-creem-magazine-at-its-most-prickly-eye-weekly/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "&#8220;recalls Creem Magazine at its most prickly&#8221; (Eye Weekly)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&quot;To point out that the staff at your local indie record store are about as tightly wound and implacable as the Taliban has already become a clich&eacute;. In contrast to that stalwart stance, Scram Magazine has become known for a distinct lack of smugness while digging through the dollar bins of history. Most pop-storians are obsessed with the failed, marginal and forgotten. Scram understands that the successful, populist and forgotten can be just as mysterious, and in this collection of reviews and essays, you&#8217;ll never be scorned by a pale, weedy boy for liking Terence Trent D&#8217;arby. In fact, its writers (including star nerds Jim O&#8217;Rourke and Rick Moody) will encourage you on in your bold and (un)original taste. If hipsterism is a temple built on Big Star and Stooges box sets, then Lost in the Grooves aims to tear down the walls with the clarion call of Kylie Minogue. Pop, after all, is about being popular, and if you want to understand popular culture, why waste time with Captain Beefheart when you can reassess Poco? Yes, the forgotten sons of California rock get multiple mentions here. But calling for a Poco revival isn&#8217;t the boldest thing in this book by far. Moody will have you reconsidering The Tubes, and Kris Kendall rights the wrongs dealt to the Dream Warriors by both industry and history. Unlike some music writing, these reviews are carefully written &#8212; as opposed to sounding like rewritten press releases &#8212; and recall Creem Magazine at its most prickly and acid. Should the comparison not be apparent to the reader, excerpts from Creem are reprinted, wink-and-nod-like, throughout its pages. Walk away right now and go back to your mid-period Sonic Youth records if you think this is irony. Lost in the Grooves is as sincere as disco and just as satisfying, providing a final home for music &#8212; from The Auteurs to Aaron Carter &#8212; that only wanted to be loved. Maybe that&#8217;s the pop difference; music that isn&#8217;t too cool to say &quot;I love you.&quot; Do you have the balls to say it back? (Brian Joseph Davis, Eye Weekly, 12/02/04) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/recalls-creem-magazine-at-its-most-prickly-eye-weekly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
