<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Eddie Hinton &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/eddie-hinton/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2006 16:13:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Get The Hinton</title>
		<link>/2006/06/13/get-the-hinton/</link>
					<comments>/2006/06/13/get-the-hinton/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2006 16:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Capricorn Records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eddie Hinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Otis Redding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stax]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I sit here today on a friend&#8217;s computer a sad, broken man after the remnants of a thunderstorm totally fried mine this past Sunday. I have pretty much lost everything I have ever written, that is to say, the originals, how they were before all the evil editors I have worked with in the past &#8230; <a href="/2006/06/13/get-the-hinton/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Get The Hinton"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>     I sit here today on a friend&#8217;s computer a sad, broken man after the remnants of a thunderstorm totally fried mine this past Sunday. I have pretty much lost everything I have ever written, that is to say, the originals, how they were before all the evil editors I have worked with in the past tried to ruin them, destroy my thoughts and ideas. I still have the print copies, expurgated and diluted as they tend to be. It is not enough.</p>
<p>     It is in times like this when I turn to some pretty deep music to try to erase the evil thoughts in my mind. The ones telling me to kill.</p>
<p>     Once again I turn to Eddie Hinton.</p>
<p>     The last, and really, only great white hope of deep soul music, Hinton wrote songs like Dan Penn, sang them like Otis Redding and played guitar like Steve Cropper. Only better. He spent a lot of time in the big recording studios in the deep South when the soul music boom of the late &#8217;60&#8217;s/early &#8217;70&#8217;s was at it&#8217;s peak. He played and wrote songs for artists like Percy Sledge, Johnny Taylor, Aretha Franklin, Sam and Dave, the Staple Singers and the list goes on and on. All this was just the start, though. It is where he shaped his sound and honed his craft.</p>
<p>      All for one reason: to strike out on his own. He got his chance around 1977 or so. The original Capricorn label wanted an album from him and he was only too eager to deliver. He poured his heart and soul, his sweat and tears, everything he had into the album and it was released. And it was fucking great. Sadly, the label started experiencing legal woes around the same time and the album trickled out to almost no response whatsoever.</p>
<p>      It broke him. Shattered his mind to the point he was a mere shell of himself. Another band followed and some recording time but soon he was homeless. A friend found him, luckily, and helped him regain a measure of himself and also helped him put out some records for Rounder Records&#8217; subsidiary Bullseye. While decent, these albums are scattershot &#8211; his vocals worn and ragged and his songs mere sketches. His guitar playing remained genius, pouring out of what was left of his shattered soul. </p>
<p>      He managed two albums before he found peace in 1995. What we have left are rare albums that are the hopy grail of soul music. I implore you to find anything with his name on it and study it. Inside those grooves are the soul of a man who could do anything before the music business ripped his life from him and left him a limp husk. </p>
<p>      Keep an eye out for an exceptionally good 3 CD series of songwriting demos put out by Zane records of Austrailia. Google them and buy those CDs. Both works-in-progress and finished songs are featured and the CDs are riveting. Also find Hard Luck Guy which was released in 1997 on the revived Capricorn label. Twenty years after screwing him and two years after his death, the label released what may actually be his best album &#8211; comprised of what he was working on before his death, it is a bittersweet listen &#8211; he seemed to have located his genius and was on the verge of putting it all back together.</p>
<p>      Listen to these albums before you sign that record deal. And anytime you just don&#8217;t feel good about what&#8217;s going on. They are classic cry in your beer albums from an artist who could have been a legend many times over. Part of me hopes you never get sad enough to appreciate them.</p>
<p>      The Music Nerd Knows&#8230;&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/06/13/get-the-hinton/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Little Street Team Work</title>
		<link>/2006/06/09/a-little-street-team-work/</link>
					<comments>/2006/06/09/a-little-street-team-work/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Homewood]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 16:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bobby Byrd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Penn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Covay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eddie Hinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jimmy Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Otis Redding]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I sit here ready to start a day full of article deadlines and some magazine consulting work, I have decided to ruminate on the next few blogs and who I will write about. A little pre-publication &#8220;street team&#8221; work if you will &#8211; you know, do some advance work and get you, the audience, &#8230; <a href="/2006/06/09/a-little-street-team-work/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "A Little Street Team Work"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>    As I sit here ready to start a day full of article deadlines and some magazine consulting work, I have decided to ruminate on the next few blogs and who I will write about. A little pre-publication &#8220;street team&#8221; work if you will &#8211; you know, do some advance work and get you, the audience, ready for some prime obscure musician/recording writing.</p>
<p>    In the next week or so I will be writing about several of my all time soul and jazz faves including soul great Don Covay (any of his albums are good, but there is one obscure blues-based CD he recorded under a group name alias I will be specifically talking about), Memphis soul titan Eddie Hinton (this guy was a genius who could do it all &#8211; write songs, play blistering guitar, sing like Otis Redding, and, sadly, have a mental breakdown so severe it cost him his career), organist and hero of mine Jimmy Smith, James Brown&#8217;s right hand man and funk-king in his own right Bobby Byrd, the original Do Right Man and brilliant songwriter Dan Penn, and maybe Polk Salad Annie&#8217;s best friend Tony Joe White as well.</p>
<p>    As you can see, I am on a major soul and jazz kick lately. Over the past year or so I have really become quite bored with rock music. While I am an intense power pop and psyche-rock fan and may decide to do some writing about The Spongetones, Dungen, Willie Wisely, Jellyfish and others of that ilk, by and large most rock is leaving me cold. I am sure it&#8217;s just a phase. For a long while, and even continuing to this day, I was up to my earholes in great alt.country music as I embraced my inner banjo-loving redneck. While the feeling isn&#8217;t as strong, I still get exciting when bands like the Bottlerockets release new albums (which they just did, the album Zoysia on Bloodshot Records) and make tour stops around the Southeast.</p>
<p>    There is so much great obscure music<br />
out there, some of it released by major bands and just forgotten about. For example, did you know both The Tokens and The Four Seasons each released great, obscure, forgotten psyche-rock albums that rank right up there with Sgt. Pepper and Pet Sounds? Bet you didn&#8217;t. Very little recent music makes me smile &#8211; but the underground stuff, whether it be vintage or new, is simply great to discover and I am hoping I can bring you to some new stuff that makes you travel down a whole different musical avenue.</p>
<p>    Well, that&#8217;s it for today. Hopefully you know at least a few of these names, or maybe it&#8217;s even better if you don&#8217;t. Do a little homework this weekend and check some of them out. Their all great &#8211; I wouldn&#8217;t tell you about them if they weren&#8217;t!</p>
<p>    The Music Nerd knows&#8230;&#8230;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/06/09/a-little-street-team-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
