<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: NRBQ PDQ 2	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2006/05/23/nrbq-pdq-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2006/05/23/nrbq-pdq-2/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 16:12:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Tony Sclafani		</title>
		<link>/2006/05/23/nrbq-pdq-2/#comment-13</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tony Sclafani]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">#comment-13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Nice post. As a longtime Q fan, I used to wonder why they never got on radio either.&#160; I think one problem was their constant label jumping. They had a stint on Kama Sutra Records in the mid 1970s, wher they released &#034;Scraps&#034; and &#034;Workshop.&#034; These efforts are both first-rate, but I think critics don&#039;t count &#039;em as among the band&#039;s best because no one can ever find &#039;em.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just for the record, NRBQ did manage to get two singles into the pop charts.&#160; The first was &#034;Stomp&#034; from their first LP, which made it to #122 in June of 1969 (that means it only ever hit the Bubbling Under chart). The second was &#034;Get That Gasoline Blues,&#034; a non-LP single that was a humorous look at the 1970s gas crisis. It made it to #70 in Feb. 74 but CANNOT be found nd can be found on &#034;Peek-A-Boo,&#034; the band&#039;s best of. It&#039;s on the &#034;RC Cola and Moon Pie&#034; compilation which is really &#034;Workshop&#034; with some songs deleted and some added. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nice post. As a longtime Q fan, I used to wonder why they never got on radio either.&nbsp; I think one problem was their constant label jumping. They had a stint on Kama Sutra Records in the mid 1970s, wher they released &quot;Scraps&quot; and &quot;Workshop.&quot; These efforts are both first-rate, but I think critics don&#8217;t count &#8217;em as among the band&#8217;s best because no one can ever find &#8217;em.</p>
<p>Just for the record, NRBQ did manage to get two singles into the pop charts.&nbsp; The first was &quot;Stomp&quot; from their first LP, which made it to #122 in June of 1969 (that means it only ever hit the Bubbling Under chart). The second was &quot;Get That Gasoline Blues,&quot; a non-LP single that was a humorous look at the 1970s gas crisis. It made it to #70 in Feb. 74 but CANNOT be found nd can be found on &quot;Peek-A-Boo,&quot; the band&#8217;s best of. It&#8217;s on the &quot;RC Cola and Moon Pie&quot; compilation which is really &quot;Workshop&quot; with some songs deleted and some added. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: pete		</title>
		<link>/2006/05/23/nrbq-pdq-2/#comment-23</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[pete]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">#comment-23</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was good to come across this post. I was searching the web to try to find a copy of &quot;Get that Gasoline Blues&quot; when I did. I&#039;m putting together a CD for my brother that&#039;s about memories of the FM station we listened to when we were both teenaged stoners, and NRBQ figures prominently (along with John Prine, among others.)The station was WPLR in New Haven Conn., and growing up on the East End of Long Island it was the only decent rock station we could pick up. During the mid to late seventies and beyond it was all we listened to. NRBQ was pretty big, not only at the station but the whole tri-state area of NY, NJ and Conn. I always thought they were from Conn. Maybe you know? I got to see them one time and all I remember was they cooked and were LOUD!!! Anyway, now I live in Nashville, and have had a chance to see Big Al a couple times here. Delbert McClinton puts on a benefit every year for The Nashville Children&#039;s Theatre which I&#039;ve been to 6 or 7 times and 2 or 3 of those Big Al was there. He usually performs with Jeffrey Steele or Gary Nichols (whom he writes with) and man, he still rips! When I first moved here I was in a used record store and came across a CD by him called &quot;Pay Before You Pump&quot; marked &quot;Demo - Not For Sale&quot; (which of course it was!) I have to say it would be an essential addition to any Q fan&#039;s collection. It&#039;s chock full of great rockabilly cuts, a couple slower paced tracks and one Zydeco-flavored track that even pokes fun at those not accustomed to that unique rhythm. One of the tracks was cut by Billy Ray Cyrus and one by The Nitty Gritty Dirt Band but neither got much airplay and neither was as good as Al&#039;s originals. The credits are a who&#039;s who of Nashville A-team players and even Elvis Costello makes a showing (yeah, Al!) Big Al just released another album titled &quot;After Hours&quot; which I immediately bought because I love him. I haven&#039;t had a chance to really listen yet but I like what I&#039;ve heard so far. BTW, if anyone out there likes balls-out, southern, rockablilly, s**t-kickin&#039; music you gotta check out Jeffrey Steele. He had a minor hit with a track called &quot;Somethin&#039; In The Water&quot; and I can&#039;t believe he hasn&#039;t gotten a major label deal of his own (although you get the feeling when you see him perform that he&#039;s just plain crazy!) His voice is phenomenal and he plays left-handed guitar like he&#039;s chokin&#039; a snake. A perfect match for Big Al. So, thanks for keeping the spirit alive for NRBQ and buy Big Al&#039;s albums, although he doesn&#039;t look like he needs the money!
Pete in Nash-vegas.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was good to come across this post. I was searching the web to try to find a copy of &#8220;Get that Gasoline Blues&#8221; when I did. I&#8217;m putting together a CD for my brother that&#8217;s about memories of the FM station we listened to when we were both teenaged stoners, and NRBQ figures prominently (along with John Prine, among others.)The station was WPLR in New Haven Conn., and growing up on the East End of Long Island it was the only decent rock station we could pick up. During the mid to late seventies and beyond it was all we listened to. NRBQ was pretty big, not only at the station but the whole tri-state area of NY, NJ and Conn. I always thought they were from Conn. Maybe you know? I got to see them one time and all I remember was they cooked and were LOUD!!! Anyway, now I live in Nashville, and have had a chance to see Big Al a couple times here. Delbert McClinton puts on a benefit every year for The Nashville Children&#8217;s Theatre which I&#8217;ve been to 6 or 7 times and 2 or 3 of those Big Al was there. He usually performs with Jeffrey Steele or Gary Nichols (whom he writes with) and man, he still rips! When I first moved here I was in a used record store and came across a CD by him called &#8220;Pay Before You Pump&#8221; marked &#8220;Demo &#8211; Not For Sale&#8221; (which of course it was!) I have to say it would be an essential addition to any Q fan&#8217;s collection. It&#8217;s chock full of great rockabilly cuts, a couple slower paced tracks and one Zydeco-flavored track that even pokes fun at those not accustomed to that unique rhythm. One of the tracks was cut by Billy Ray Cyrus and one by The Nitty Gritty Dirt Band but neither got much airplay and neither was as good as Al&#8217;s originals. The credits are a who&#8217;s who of Nashville A-team players and even Elvis Costello makes a showing (yeah, Al!) Big Al just released another album titled &#8220;After Hours&#8221; which I immediately bought because I love him. I haven&#8217;t had a chance to really listen yet but I like what I&#8217;ve heard so far. BTW, if anyone out there likes balls-out, southern, rockablilly, s**t-kickin&#8217; music you gotta check out Jeffrey Steele. He had a minor hit with a track called &#8220;Somethin&#8217; In The Water&#8221; and I can&#8217;t believe he hasn&#8217;t gotten a major label deal of his own (although you get the feeling when you see him perform that he&#8217;s just plain crazy!) His voice is phenomenal and he plays left-handed guitar like he&#8217;s chokin&#8217; a snake. A perfect match for Big Al. So, thanks for keeping the spirit alive for NRBQ and buy Big Al&#8217;s albums, although he doesn&#8217;t look like he needs the money!<br />
Pete in Nash-vegas.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
