<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Yarbirds &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/yarbirds/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 03:51:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>The Graham Gouldman Thing</title>
		<link>/2006/12/10/the-graham-gouldman-thing/</link>
					<comments>/2006/12/10/the-graham-gouldman-thing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[djbrian]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 03:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[60s Pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hollies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mindebenders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Total Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yarbirds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the mid-1960s Graham Gouldman was a one-man Goffin/King or Boyce &#038; Hart. The British musician and songwriter wrote perfect pop songs that were totally of their time, and which were popularized by other, better-known acts. Gouldman penned the two best songs The Hollies ever recorded (&#8220;Bus Stop&#8221; and &#8220;Look Through Any Window&#8221;) two of &#8230; <a href="/2006/12/10/the-graham-gouldman-thing/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "The Graham Gouldman Thing"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the mid-1960s Graham Gouldman was a one-man Goffin/King or Boyce &#038; Hart. The British musician and songwriter wrote perfect pop songs that were totally of their time, and which were popularized by other, better-known acts.  Gouldman penned the two best songs The Hollies ever recorded (&#8220;Bus Stop&#8221; and &#8220;Look Through Any Window&#8221;) two of the better tracks done by The Yardbirds (&#8220;For Your Love&#8221; and &#8220;Heart Full of Soul&#8221;) and also provided material for Herman&#8217;s Hermits, P.J. Proby, Wayne Fontana . . . </p>
<p>In &#8217;68 Gouldman &#8211; who had previously been part of two different bands, both of them flops &#8211;  decided it was time to put his own versions of some of his songs on record.  John Paul Jones (Francoise Hardy&#8217;s playmate, and later bassist of Led Zeppelin) was brought on board as arranger and co-producer. Some top-of-the-line sessions musicians took up instruments. And Gouldman sat down and cobbled together a workbook of songs that had been hits for other artists, as well as some new and previously unrecorded material.</p>
<p>What came out is a record that should be generally regarded as a Mod-era classic, right alongside The Beatles&#8217; Rubber Soul, The Kinks&#8217; Face to Face, and early recordings by The Who, as well as the afore-mentioned Hollies and Yardbirds. But the album wasn&#8217;t even released in Gouldman&#8217;s native land, and only managed to hit the lower reaches of the Billboard Top 100 in the U.S. </p>
<p>The artist/band Gouldman most sounds like on this record is Emitt Rhodes and The Merry-Go-Round. Gouldman the vocalist has a lisp, and he sings in that almost girlish way that Rhodes does. The arrangements and the production of the material on The G.G. Thing are bubblegumy poppy, a la The Merry-Go-Round &#8211;  that kind of bubblegum where Pure Pop meets Mod Cool.</p>
<p>Gouldman later become a member of The Mindbenders, before the 70s saw him and another Mindbender form 10CC.  Later into the 70s he did the soundtrack to the Farrah Fawcett movie, Sunburn. </p>
<p> In 2004 BMG reissued The Graham Gouldman Thing, and anybody who&#8217;s into 60&#8217;s Mod pop should thank them.  It is one of the best records of its kind. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/12/10/the-graham-gouldman-thing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
