<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>chipmunks &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/chipmunks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 06:51:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>&#8220;nothing against Christgau&#8221; (Washington City Paper)</title>
		<link>/2006/03/09/nothing-against-christgau-washington-city-paper/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/09/nothing-against-christgau-washington-city-paper/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 06:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Reviews (cont.)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chipmunks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curtis mayfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[george pelecanos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go-betweens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robert christgau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington city paper]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cashews Get Their Due: George Pelecanos is somewhat taken aback when asked to talk about his contribution to Lost in the Grooves: Scram&#8217;s Capricious Guide to the Music You Missed. &#8220;I got an e-mail from my agent a couple years ago,&#8221; says the Silver Spring&#8211;&#202;based writer. Scram, a magazine &#8220;dedicated to rooting out the cashews &#8230; <a href="/2006/03/09/nothing-against-christgau-washington-city-paper/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "&#8220;nothing against Christgau&#8221; (Washington City Paper)"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cashews Get Their Due: George Pelecanos is somewhat taken aback when asked to talk about his contribution to Lost in the Grooves: Scram&rsquo;s Capricious Guide to the Music You Missed. &ldquo;I got an e-mail from my agent a couple years ago,&rdquo; says the Silver Spring&ndash;&Ecirc;based writer. Scram, a magazine &ldquo;dedicated to rooting out the cashews in the bridge mix of unpopular culture,&rdquo; wanted him to write a piece about underappreciated music. &ldquo;I just sent it. I never talked to them or anything,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;Then this book shows up.&rdquo; Lost in the Grooves compiles essays&mdash;sometimes of just a few lines&mdash;about perennial critics&rsquo; darlings (the Go-Betweens&rsquo; 16 Lovers Lane), odd faves of odd people (Vivian Stanshall&rsquo;s Men Opening Umbrellas Ahead), albums you weren&rsquo;t supposed to like (Alvin and the Chipmunks&rsquo; The Alvin Show), and whatever else its writers&mdash;including locals Ken Barnes (USA Today, &rsquo;70s zines Flash and Fusion), and Vern Stoltz (Cannot Be Obsolete) and Memphis, Tenn.&ndash;based Washington City Paper contributor Andrew Earles&mdash;favor. Pelecanos wrote about Curtis Mayfield&rsquo;s 1973 Curtom release Back to the World. &ldquo;I just picked a record that I thought was really underappreciated in its category, especially coming after Superfly.&rdquo; The overlooked disc &ldquo;was of a time when people were making records that were sort of thematic,&rdquo; says Pelecanos, and it&rsquo;s easy to see why the crime novelist and story editor of HBO&rsquo;s The Wire would relate to lines like these: &ldquo;In these city streets&mdash;everywhere/You got to be careful/Where you move your feet, and how you part your hair.&rdquo; Pelecanos&rsquo; review ends with a shot at the dean of rock critics: &ldquo;Robert Christgau gave this a &lsquo;C.&rsquo; Another reason, in my opinion, to check it out.&rdquo; Pelecanos is quick to point out that he has nothing against Christgau, but, he says, &ldquo;I object to that kind of criticism&#8230;. A guy, or a woman, sits in a dark room for a year and writes a book, and then someone blows it off with a D-minus or whatever.&rdquo; Pelecanos&rsquo; appreciation for music is almost as well-known as his novels, which chronicle a Washington far from filibusters and presidential coronations. The &ldquo;tour music&rdquo; section of his Web site offers a playlist much like that in Lost in the Grooves: When he hits the road to promote his new book, Drama City, in March, his CD wallet will be stocked with Slobberbone, Lalo Schifrin, the Isley Brothers, Iron + Wine, War, and Graham Parker. And his previous novel, Hard Revolution, featured a &ldquo;soundtrack&rdquo; CD given away at readings. Next for Pelecanos, besides the book tour, is news on whether The Wire will be picked up for a fourth season. The future of the drama may be grim, given HBO Chair Chris Albrecht&rsquo;s quip that &ldquo;I have received a telegram from every viewer of The Wire&mdash;all 250 of them.&rdquo; Perhaps Scram should cover unpopular TV in its next book. (Pamela Murray Winters, Washington City Paper, 2/11/05) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/09/nothing-against-christgau-washington-city-paper/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
