<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sydney austalia &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/sydney-austalia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 09:06:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Mesmerizer</title>
		<link>/2006/03/08/mesmerizer/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/08/mesmerizer/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2006 09:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[13th floor elevators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artists (exclusive MP3s/CDs)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate watchband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citadel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deniz tek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lipstick Killers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio birdman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sydney austalia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Lipstick Killers&#8217; Mesmerizer is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive. Click to sample the music or purchase. The Lipstick Killers Mesmerizer (Citadel, Australia, 1984) On the strength of a Deniz Tek-produced 45 issued by Bomp subsidiary Voxx in 1979, Sydney&#8217;s Lipstick Killers decamped for Los Angeles and dreams of Northern hemisphere success. They lasted &#8230; <a href="/2006/03/08/mesmerizer/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Mesmerizer"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Lipstick Killers&#8217; <em>Mesmerizer</em> is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive. <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+102&#038;artist=89" target="_blank">Click</a> to sample the music or purchase.  </p>
<p>The Lipstick Killers <em>Mesmerizer</em> (Citadel, Australia, 1984)  </p>
<p>On the strength of a Deniz Tek-produced 45 issued by Bomp subsidiary Voxx in 1979, Sydney&rsquo;s Lipstick Killers decamped for Los Angeles and dreams of Northern hemisphere success. They lasted a year in the cozy grime of the Tropicana Motel and a bug-infested Silverlake apartment, playing about a dozen gigs, including a Brian Jones memorial at the Whisky and at Madame Wong&rsquo;s with the Plimsouls. Mesmerizer is the document of one of these shows, recorded on cassette by Flesh Eater Chris D., cleaned up nicely and released posthumously on Radio Birdman crony &ldquo;Brother&rdquo; John Needham&rsquo;s Citadel imprint. In the absence of an official studio album, this high energy set stands as slightly sloppy but irresistible evidence of the band&rsquo;s magic. Over twelve songs, including terrific covers of the Chocolate Watchband&rsquo;s &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s Talk About Girls&rdquo; and the Elevators&rsquo; &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve Got Levitation,&rdquo; the Lipstick Killers swagger like the Hindu gods of their signature song, all power chords, tribal drums and perfectly controlled frenzy. The band&rsquo;s originals come across like unknown frat rock standards gene-spliced with a finely honed blend of psychedelia and DIY punk energy. Insinuation was their strong suit: &ldquo;Dying Boy&rsquo;s Crawl&rdquo; and &ldquo;Strange Flash&rdquo; get right under your skin and pull you bodily towards the music. Maybe a band this tight and moody was nothing special on the Sydney scene, but they must have blown their L.A. competition sideways. Unfortunately, the usual band problems intruded&#8211;mental illness, money, the singer getting a day job to pay rent on the communal flat&#8211;and the Killers called it quits. The members eventually wound their way back to Australia, where they still occasionally play as the Lipstick Killers. When I saw them open for Radio Birdman in 2002 they fulfilled every promise of <em>Mesmerizer</em> and more. (Kim Cooper, from the book <em>Lost in the Grooves</em>)  </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/08/mesmerizer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
