<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>piano rock &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/piano-rock/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2006 08:26:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Jumping Into The Fray- My First Next Big Thing</title>
		<link>/2006/04/28/jumping-into-the-fray-the/</link>
					<comments>/2006/04/28/jumping-into-the-fray-the/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Edelman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2006 08:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alex Edelman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obscure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[piano rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rolling Stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Fray]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some of you old timers may know it.&#160;It&#8217;s an odd type of thrill. The idea that you have been privy to a secret that only a select few know. Like being in on the inside joke before it became known to others. It&#8217;s&#160;seeing a band&#8211; before they hit it big. U-2 at the Paradise Rock &#8230; <a href="/2006/04/28/jumping-into-the-fray-the/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Jumping Into The Fray- My First Next Big Thing"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some of you old timers may know it.&nbsp;It&#8217;s an odd type of thrill. The idea that you have been privy to a secret that only a select few know. Like being in on the inside joke before it became known to others. It&#8217;s&nbsp;seeing a band&#8211; before they hit it big.</p>
<p>U-2 at the Paradise Rock Lounge in 1983,</p>
<p>The Rolling Stones open with Mozart in 1562 (I kid)</p>
<p>Dave Matthews in a coffee shop in Charlottesville, VA in 1991.</p>
<p>Jeff Buckley at Sin-&eacute; a few years later.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Every band has had its modest startings, and, being a teenager, I had never really heard a band before they hit it big.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Until I heard <a title="The Fray" href="https://www.thefray.net/" target="_self">the Fray </a>last November.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It was a cold night on November 5, 2005&#8211; exactly the time and place where one might find musical gold. The Orpheum is an&nbsp;alleyway theatre at the end of Hamilton Place in Boston&rsquo;s Park Street Gardens, the border between the gleaming neighborhoods that hold the 40,000 seat Boston Garden arena, and <img loading="lazy" title="How To Save a Life" height="199" alt="How To Save a Life" src="https://www.sonymusicstore.com/coverimages/SME_0101_EK_093931.70Q_200x200_72dpi_RGB.jpg" width="200" align="left" border="0" />the blocks that once held the infamous Chinatown Combat Zone&#8211; where there are clubs that can&#8217;t fit 40, much less 40,000. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The funny thing is, that night; no one is coming to see this unknown band from Denver, CO. They are coming to see Piano Rock living legend/maestro/creative genius <a title="Ben Folds" href="https://www.benfolds.com/" target="_self">Ben Folds</a>, the main act that the&nbsp;Fray is opening for. While the band begins its set, most of the people who were able to get tickets to Folds&rsquo; concert are still clambering off the Boston Trolleys (Or &ldquo;T&rsquo;s,&rdquo; as us locals affectionately refer to them). The ages&nbsp;range from teenaged babysitters to middle-aged baby boomers, and they all stumble down the dark street, away from the Boston Common, towards the Orpheum&rsquo;s grimy exterior, in search of their bi-annual Folds fix.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Inside, Isaac Slade (see photo at right), the front man of The Fray, <img loading="lazy" title="Isaac Slade" height="325" alt="Isaac Slade" src="https://thefray.net/photos/live2004/images/12.jpg" width="325" align="right" border="0" />launches into the piano solo that heralds the song that&nbsp;the band has now become known for (&ldquo;Over My Head&rdquo;). Slade and his mates have come a long way from their hometown of Denver, Colorado, and they are enjoying the new adulation that comes from a national tour. The theatre is less then half full, but gradually, all private conversations cease, and the members of the Fray have the full attention of the crowd. Many cheer&hellip; but others simply see the Fray as the last buffer between them and Ben Folds&mdash; they wait for the set to be over.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I leave the theatre awed at the musical genius of Ben Folds, but a little nagging thought pushes its way into my head. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Who in the hell are The Fray to make me want to hear them again? So I figure on doing what I always do when I hear a band whose songs stick in my head. Listen to their best work over and over, until I get tired of them, and eventually, when they fade further down on my playlist and slip from my mind, I look for a new band. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Fast forward to April 26<sup>th</sup>. The Fray is still on my mind. I find their album <em>How to Save a Life&nbsp;</em>(buy it <a title="How To Save a Life" href="https://www.shopbenchmark.net/site/fray/" target="_self">here</a>)&nbsp;to be the best freshman work I have ever heard, and the title song to be melodic, adrenaline-filled, and touching. When I hear their signature track &ldquo;Over My Head (Cable Car),&rdquo; on the radio in Arizona, or on the top 10 list on iTunes, or an article about them in <em>Rolling Stone </em>magazine, I get excited, and I know that, even if I missed U-2 in &rsquo;83&mdash;I saw the Fray in &rsquo;05.</p>
<p>Take this home and chew on it.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s delicious.</p>
<p>Alex E.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>P.S. I will keep writing about these guys. They rule.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/04/28/jumping-into-the-fray-the/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
