<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Club Wow &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/club-wow/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 02:10:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Deadbeat Poets &#8220;Notes from the Underground&#8221; CD is LITG&#8217;s featured release</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2007/08/27/deadbeatpoets/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2007/08/27/deadbeatpoets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2007 02:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[backdoor men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Ash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Club Wow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deadbeat Poets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infidels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[napoleon in rags]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ohio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stiv Bators]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deadbeat Poets&#39; Notes from the Underground is a featured Lost in the Grooves release. To preview and download single or multiple tracks, or to purchase the CD, click here. Deadbeat Poets press release: The Deadbeat Poets were formed in Youngstown, Ohio in the summer of 2006. The band consists of veteran Ohio musicians with eclectic &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2007/08/27/deadbeatpoets/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Deadbeat Poets &#8220;Notes from the Underground&#8221; CD is LITG&#8217;s featured release"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Deadbeat Poets&#39; <em>Notes from the Underground</em> is a featured Lost in the Grooves release. To preview and download single or multiple tracks, or to purchase the CD, click <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/store/cd_info.php?id=MMG+346" target="_blank">here</a>.  </p>
<p>Deadbeat Poets press release: <br />The Deadbeat Poets were formed in Youngstown, Ohio in the summer of 2006. The band consists of veteran Ohio musicians with eclectic credentials: Frank Secich (Blue Ash, Club Wow, Stiv Bators Band), Terry Hartman (Backdoor Men, Napoleon In Rags, Terry &amp; The Tornadoes), Pete Drivere (Infidels, Pretty Demons) and John Koury (Infidels, Slackjaw). Their debut album (which was recorded over the first few months of 2007 at Youngstown&#39;s Ampreon Recorder) is now released on <a href="http://www.PopDetective.com/" target="_blank">Pop Detective Records</a> and is available online through Lost in the Grooves and MMG, and in Japan on Vivid Sound Records. Also, making guest appearances on the album are Bill &quot;Cupid&quot; Bartolin on guitar and Chris Leonardi on piano and organ.</p>
<p>Soon, you&#39;ll be able to sit back and relax (pop the top and set the sail) as the Deadbeat Poets take you on a timely journey. To such places&#8230;. romantic places like Beaver Falls (via Mahoningtown) you&#39;ll go. You&#39;ll travel to the exotic northside of Youngstown, Cleveland, the depths of the Atlantic Ocean, Toronto, Geneva-On-The-Lake, New York, LA, London, the far reaches of outer space, Paris, Mt. Pilot, The Bering Sea, St. Paul and of course Buffalo, NY. You&#39;ll meet fun lovin&#39;, sex-crazed aliens in &quot;The Truth About Flying Saucers&quot;. You&#39;ll hear the tale of the legendary Ray Robinson who once roamed the dark, back-country roads of Western, PA in &quot;The Green Man&quot;. You&#39;ll encounter semi-romantic mountain men and their passions in &quot;Ernest T&quot; and ride along with Stiv Bators as he once terrorized the western world in &quot;The Stiv Bators Ghost Tour&quot;. You&#39;ll find out the connection between Ernest Hemmingway and Gertrude Stein and French bidets in &quot;Where Was I When I Needed Me?&quot; You&#39;ll raise glasses and bottles with the lads in &quot;No Island Like The Mind, No Ship Like Beer&quot; and be sadly disappointed by gangsters and thieves as &quot;The Goody Wagon&quot; never arrives. If floating in a psychedelic flutter is your inclination then &quot;What Part Of Cognitive Dissonance Don&#39;t You Understand?&quot; will probably be your cup of tea. Then again, you may find that after all of this &#8230;..well that &quot;It&#39;s Nothing&quot; to you. Then again, you may start getting &quot;A Funny Little Feeling&quot; that you will enjoy the Deadbeat Poets.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2007/08/27/deadbeatpoets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
