<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sir henry at rawlinson end &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/sir-henry-at-rawlinson-end/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2006 23:56:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Rawlinson End movie</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/06/29/rawlinson-end-movie/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/06/29/rawlinson-end-movie/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert Dayton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2006 23:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bonzo dog band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Dayton: Going Great!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sir henry at rawlinson end]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivian stanshall]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Why does the movie &#8220;Sir Henry At Rawlinson End&#8221; get such a bad rap amongst average film goers and even some die hard Bonzo Dog Band fans alike? (tho it was well received critically upon release) Being a huge fan of Vivian Stanshall, he&#8217;s one of my Personal Style Gods, I went into this hard &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/06/29/rawlinson-end-movie/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Rawlinson End movie"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why does the movie &#8220;Sir Henry At Rawlinson End&#8221; get such a bad rap amongst average film goers and even some die hard Bonzo Dog Band fans alike? (tho it was well received critically upon release)<br />
Being a huge fan of Vivian Stanshall, he&#8217;s one of my Personal Style Gods, I went into this hard to find film suitably wary, yet left thinking that this is a perfect cinematic hallmark of whom some call the last of the British Eccentrics.<br />
Everyone in the room of fifteen people that I was in truly enjoyed this movie and some had never even heard of Vivian Stanshall.<br />
Who was Vivian Stanshall? Impossible to encapsulate. Moustachioed drinking buddy of Keith Moon and member of The Beatles&#8217; favourite band The Bonzo Dog Band. I regard The Bonzos as the greatest rock band of all time. Yes, they were funny but they were also nuanced and handy with a ballad, truly witty and catchy songsmiths that made things explode onstage. Their pastiches and wild dandyisms predated glam.<br />
(Just read a great quote in a 1973 ish of Creem yesterday that really helps to solidify this theory: &#8220;Melody Maker&#8217;s Chris Welch is probably right when he says that if they had stuck together a few more months, they would have been the kings of Glam-rock. That&#8217;s the breaks.&#8221;<br />
VIVIAN STANSHALL:<br />
<a href="http://photobucket.com/" target="_blank"><img src="http://i59.photobucket.com/albums/g295/moustachedpainless/vivbig.jpg" border="0" alt="Photobucket - Video and Image Hosting"></a></p>
<p>Stanshall later created a certain mythology around a mad aristocratic family that meandered in a crumbling castle named Rawlinson End. Representing the hazy decline of The British empire that he performed as radio plays regularly on John Peel&#8217;s show.<br />
The movie was written by Stanshall who also plays a small role. One may recognize some familar faces if you&#8217;ve seen a few British films&#8230;<br />
No real rising or falling action, it&#8217;s just a strange snapshot of ghost exorcisms, prisoners of war on the manor, etcetera, there is a plot or few in there! Incredibly witty, many of us wanted to view it again to catch all of the jokes and goings on. &#8220;If I had all the money I&#8217;d spent on drink I&#8217;d spend it on drink!&#8221; Utterly loony.<br />
This movie is completely unmarketable and delightful. A perfect visual representation of the Rawlinson End mythos.<br />
When the director was asked why he filmed it entirely in sepiatone he didn&#8217;t reply. The answer is obvious.<br />
Reccommended for fans of Guy Maddin and fans of British comedy of which this should be placed highly in the pantheon of.<br />
<a href="http://photobucket.com/" target="_blank"><img src="http://i59.photobucket.com/albums/g295/moustachedpainless/sirhenryat.jpg" border="0" alt="Photobucket - Video and Image Hosting"></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/06/29/rawlinson-end-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
