<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>names &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tags/names/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 21:49:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Dream Lake Ukelele Band</title>
		<link>/2006/03/22/dream-lake-ukelele-band/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/22/dream-lake-ukelele-band/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 21:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dream Lake Ukelele Band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[langley schools music project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweetness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thrift store record]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ukelele]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dream Lake Ukulele Band is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive. Click to sample the music or purchase. Dream Lake Ukulele Band Dream Lake Ukulele Band (Crest, 1976) What do you get when you cross twenty-seven ukuleles, a Little Marcy record, and the Langley Schools Music Project? The result is a bizarre hybrid called the &#8230; <a href="/2006/03/22/dream-lake-ukelele-band/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Dream Lake Ukelele Band"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dream Lake Ukulele Band is a Lost in the Grooves exclusive. <a href="https://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+262&#038;artist=193" target="_blank">Click</a> to sample the music or purchase.</p>
<p>Dream Lake Ukulele Band<br /> Dream Lake Ukulele Band<br /> (Crest, 1976)</p>
<p> What do you get when you cross twenty-seven ukuleles, a Little Marcy record, and the Langley Schools Music Project? The result is a bizarre hybrid called the Dream Lake Ukulele Band, a Florida school group whose performances are documented on Crest Records, a New York vanity label. The back cover shows twenty-seven grade school aged students, all wearing white shirts and red vests, the boys also wearing neckties. Sound boring? Not when every kid is smiling and holding a ukulele. </p>
<p> The lead-off, &ldquo;There&rsquo;s So Many, Many Ways,&rdquo; is one of the more charming Christian songs around, but I&rsquo;m sure my opinion is altered by the sheer innocent joy of twenty-seven children&rsquo;s voices singing in harmony while strumming their ukuleles. That spirit changes a bit though, when the songs veer off into the Bicentennial patriotic songs that fill the rest of Side 1. Such lyrics as &quot;My Sunday school teacher loves me when I am never late&quot; preceded by &quot;God loves when I learn to shoot the gun&quot; makes one wish that the band director would have been cool enough to be teaching the kids David Bowie songs.</p>
<p> Fortunately, Side 2 has the perfect antidote, for that is where the children present and sing their own original compositions. Compiled under headings such as &quot;Wish Songs,&quot; &quot;Name Songs,&quot; and &quot;Music Songs,&quot; each features a progression of five to ten kids strumming and singing solo. These aren&rsquo;t loud bratty kids singing &quot;Tomorrow&quot; at the top of their lungs, but more often small waif-like girls singing with very timid voices.&nbsp; My heart melts whenever I hear one girl who sings, &quot;I am Mary, I like to play the ukulele&quot; or another girl whose verse starts by saying her parents are always busy, and then proceeds with &quot;Daddy is a band director, Mommy is a piano teacher, I love them.&quot; This record is listed as being Volume Seven, which definitely makes me wish that I also had volumes One through Six. (Vern Stolz, from the book Lost in the Grooves) </p>
<p>Are you a member of the Dream Lake Ukelele Band? If so, please <a href="https://litg.richardschave.com//feedback" target="_blank">contact</a> us!&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/22/dream-lake-ukelele-band/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
