<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>writers &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/writers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 11:21:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>About</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/about-0/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/about-0/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 11:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[anthology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Contributors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost in the grooves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[record reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LOST IN THE GROOVES: SCRAM&#8217;S CAPRICIOUS GUIDE TO THE MUSIC YOU MISSED a new anthology celebrating the greatest records you&#8217;ve never heard about the contributors Brooke Alberts is an inveterate folk-head who writes for the L.A. based Folkworks, plays whistle in as many Irish traditional sessions as possible, and loves hot whiskey and a great &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/about-0/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "About"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>LOST IN THE GROOVES: SCRAM&#8217;S CAPRICIOUS GUIDE TO THE MUSIC YOU MISSED<br />
a new anthology celebrating the greatest records you&#8217;ve never heard</p>
<p>about the contributors</p>
<p>Brooke Alberts is an inveterate folk-head who writes for the L.A. based Folkworks, plays whistle in as many Irish traditional sessions as possible, and loves hot whiskey and a great bowl of New England clam chowder.</p>
<p>Mike Appelstein is the former editor/publisher of Caught in Flux zine. Currently he is an occasional DJ and freelance writer, as well as webmaster of the pretty-much-official Young Marble Giants website. He lives in St. Louis, MO. Visit www.appelstein.com for details and contact info.</p>
<p>Jake Austen edits Roctober, the journal of popular music&#8217;s dynamic obscurities, and (with wife Jacqueline) produces the children&#8217;s dance show Chic-A-Go-Go. His work has appeared in The Cartoon Music Book, Playboy, The Spice Girls Comicbook and Bubblegum Music is the Naked Truth. His books include A Friendly Game of Poker and a forthcoming idiosyncratic history of rock on television. Please visit www.roctober.com</p>
<p>Peter Bagge is an &#8220;alternative&#8221; cartoonist, best known for his comic book &#8220;Hate,&#8221; although he has many other credits to his name. Please refer to www.peterbagge.com for further details.</p>
<p>The Bengala is a matrimonial art collective consisting of Benjamin Tischer and Gala Verdugo. They love music almost as much as each other. They also help put out K48 Magazine, which is way rad. Contact: bengala@verizon.net</p>
<p>Tosh Berman is the publisher and editor of Tam Tam Books. He is currently publishing the works of Boris Vian as well as Guy Debord and Serge Gainsbourg. For further information check out www.tamtambooks.com</p>
<p>Jon Bernhardt has been a DJ on WMBR-FM since 1983, and plays theremin for The Lothars and The Pee Wee Fist (CDs available at http://www.wobblymusic.com)./ He lives in Somerville, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>Derrick Bostrom performed with the Meat Puppets from 1980 to 1986. Though he still maintains the band&#8217;s archives his own music can be heard under the moniker &#8220;Today&#8217;s Sounds.&#8221;</p>
<p>Joe Boucher lives in Brooklyn with his two non-specific liberal arts degrees; his attempt to get a third did not go well. He loves and appreciates his family and friends. Employers sense in him a denial of their values. He could stand to drop a few pounds, too.</p>
<p>Carl Cafarelli&#8217;s three all-time favorite bands are the Beatles, the Ramones and the Flashcubes. So there. Carl writes for Goldmine magazine and co-hosts (with Dana Bonn) This is Rock &#8216;n&#8217; Roll Radio, &#8220;the best three hours of radio on the whole friggin&#8217; planet!,&#8221; Sunday nights from 9 to midnight Eastern at wxxe.org. Weekly e-mail playlists are available from ccdatsme@aol.com</p>
<p>Kevin Carhart is a freelance writer based in the SF Bay Area. He is obsessed with music, comics and women. Come to http://carhart.com/~kevin for an unruly pile of comics, reviews, dreams, circles, lists, drawings, stories and creations.</p>
<p>Born and raised in East LA, documentary filmmaker Sean Carrillo was a member of the guerilla art group ASCO and co-founded Troy Caf</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/03/09/about-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
