<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Metal Mike Saunders &#8211; Lost In The Grooves</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/category/tags/metal-mike-saunders/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2006 03:53:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Blue Ash</title>
		<link>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/10/15/blue-ash-1/</link>
					<comments>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/10/15/blue-ash-1/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2006 03:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Ash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frank Secich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper/ LITG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metal Mike Saunders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ohio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power pop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small faces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Who]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Blue Ash is a Lost in the Grooves artist. Click to sample the music or purchase tracks from Around Again &#8211; A Collection of Rarities From the Vault 1972-1979. And keep an eye peeled to Frank Secich&#8217;s Blue Ash blog here at LITG for news, photos and insights straight from the band. This reissue (of &#8230; <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/10/15/blue-ash-1/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "Blue Ash"</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blue Ash is a Lost in the Grooves artist. <a href="http://www.maryattmusic.com/search_results_cd.php?cd=MMG+292&#038;artist=206" target="_blank">Click</a> to sample the music or purchase tracks from <em>Around Again &#8211; A Collection of Rarities From the Vault 1972-1979</em>. And keep an eye peeled to Frank Secich&#8217;s <a href="https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/?p=979" target="_self">Blue Ash blog</a> here at LITG for news, photos and insights straight from the band. This reissue (of a double CD first put out by the good folks at Not Lame) is just the start, as we&#8217;ll soon be digging deeper into the Blue Ash vaults for songs never before heard by fans.</p>
<p>Metal Mike Saunders provided this vintage record review for the <em>Lost in the Grooves</em> anthology:</p>
<blockquote><p>Blue Ash <em>No More, No Less</em> (Mercury, 1973)</p>
<p>&ldquo;I Remember A Time&rdquo; could do for Blue Ash what &ldquo;Mr. Tambourine Man&rdquo; did for the Byrds: the start of a brilliant career, a Number One hit, instant mythology. The guitar intro lasts all of five seconds before Jimmy Kendzor and Frank Secich&#8217;s voices come in, oozing of everything the Byrds and Lovin&#8217; Spoonful ever promised, the soaring harmonies in the chorus driving over jangling lead guitar work. It&#8217;s the sound of tomorrow right here today, it&#8217;s the perfect folk-rock single. It&#8217;s beautiful, that&#8217;s what.</p>
<p>This is one of the most spirited, powerful debuts ever from an American group. <em>No More, No Less</em> opens with &ldquo;Have you Seen Her,&rdquo; a fast rocker kicked off by four whomps on David Evans&#8217; snare. This is the one that makes me think of The Who; the lead guitar is pure West Coast, though.</p>
<p>&quot;Just Another Game&rdquo; is the one quiet song, an effective tonedown before &ldquo;I Remember A Time.&rdquo; &ldquo;Plain To See&rdquo; is similar to &ldquo;I Remember A Time&rdquo; in the way its simple, compelling melody rocks out with vocal harmonies framed over a trebly Byrds guitar sound.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Here We Go Again&rdquo; follows, midway between the hardest and softest numbers on the first side. What&#8217;s great here are the group vocals on top of the tuff folk-rock cum hard rock instrumental sound; it&#8217;s like killing two birds with one stone, the whole premise behind the old and new Mod groups (Small Faces, early Who, the Sweet), not to mention the hard pop masterpiece known to the world as &ldquo;Do Ya.&rdquo;</p>
<p>By the time this album ends, there&#8217;s no doubt about it, Blue Ash have got themselves one hell of a debut LP that may send fellow stateside groups like Stories, the Raspberries, and Big Star running back to the woodshed to come up with music even better than their present stuff. (Mike Saunders)</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.lostinthegrooves.com/2006/10/15/blue-ash-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
